<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jan Zilinsky - academic site. Political science.</title>
    <link>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jan Zilinsky - academic site. Political science.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 14:33:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zilinskyjan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is New</title>
      <link>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 14:33:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>“Trying to understand how Jeff Flake is leaning? We analyzed his Twitter feed.” Washington Post, Monkey Cage. with Gregory Eady, Joshua Tucker &amp;amp; Jonathan Nagler
Methodology: Calculating ideology of political actors based on their social media content.
&amp;ndash;
My paper on satisfaction with democracy was published on January 31, 2019. The journal is open access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abridged Research Statement</title>
      <link>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 13:50:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/statement/</guid>
      <description>I study how people with political objectives convey economic data, compete for office, and how they apply persuasion strategies in an environment where much of the electorate does not seek &amp;ndash; or even actively avoids &amp;ndash; direct exposure to political messages.
Politics now permeates into citizens&amp;rsquo; screens, pockets, and any room where people carry cell phones. Many observers are concerned that inflammatory news, permanent campaigning, populist rhetoric, and echo chambers are eroding democracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 15:02:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Recent/upcoming opportunities to meet:
Provo (July 2018) Boston (Late August 2018) Abu Dhabi (January 2019) Chicago (April 2019) Boston (Mid-July 2019) Washington, D.C. (Late August 2019)
New York (most of the year)
I value face-to-face conversations with other social scientists, journalists, and other people.
If you are passing through the area and we have similar research interests, or if we follow each other on Twitter, or if you would like to chat about economics, politics, or data science, feel free to reach out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 19:37:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Summary of Teaching Experience  TA for various political science courses at NYU (listed below). Head Teaching Fellow for David Laibson’s and Andrei Shleifer’s Behavioral Economics course at Harvard. TA for Matt Taddy’s Big Data course at Chicago Booth. Some of my teaching notes and slides are posted on my OSF repository.  Current instructional activity: Advising undergraduate students on research design, data manipulation, interpreting and communicating empirical results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/teaching_simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 19:37:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/teaching_simple/</guid>
      <description>Current instructional activity: Advising undergraduate students on research design, data manipulation, interpreting and communicating empirical results.
Undergraduate politics classes taught at NYU  Examining the 2016 Election - Inequality, Populism, and Voting. Data Fellow. Advanced seminar for juniors and seniors in American politics led by Professor Jonathan Nagler. Biology of Politics. Data Fellow. Course taught by Professor Chris Dawes. Introduction to Political Theory. Teaching assistant to Professor Dimitri Landa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 19:37:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Publications Democratic deconsolidation revisited: Young Europeans are not dissatisfied with democracy Research &amp;amp; Politics PDF (open-access) | Data &amp;amp; Code | Show BibTex citation @article{millennials_democracy, author = {Jan Zilinsky}, title ={Democratic deconsolidation revisited: Young Europeans are not dissatisfied with democracy}, journal = {Research &amp;amp; Politics}, volume = {6}, number = {1}, year = {2019}, URL = {https://doi.org/10.1177/2053168018814332} } 
How Many People Live in Political Bubbles on Social Media?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 19:37:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zilinskyjan.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My research investigates the capacity of political entrepreneurs to influence voting, media consumption, and public opinion with both digital and conventional tools. I am interested in the power and constraints of institutions and individuals to structure awareness, beliefs, and narratives about the economy.
I am a Ph.D. candidate in the Department of Politics at NYU and a Research Associate at the Social Media and Political Participation Lab. My ongoing work includes predictions of economic sentiment around the world with disciplined approaches to model selection inspired by machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>